financeandinsurances.com 2014-11-01

# Privacy Policy

When you access www.financeandinsurances.com we use technology to collect information indirectly such as your Internet address which is then kept in our Internet access logs.

We collect information directly from you in a number of ways. One way is through the use of cookies. Cookies are small files of information which save and retrieve information about your visit to our site - for example, how you entered our site, how you navigated through the site, and what information was of interest to you. The cookies we use identify you merely as a number. (If you are uncomfortable regarding cookies use, please keep in mind you can disable cookies on your computer by changing the settings in preferences or options menu in your browser.)

We also collect information when you give it to us. For example you may wish to register to use the message posting facility called 'Patient feedback'. When we collect this type of information, we will notify you as to why we are asking for information and how this information will be used. It is completely up to you whether or not you want to provide it.

**How do we use this information?**

We analyse it to see what is most effective about our site, to help us identify ways to improve it, and to make it more effective. We may also use data for other purposes, which we would describe to you at the point we collect the information.

**Will we disclose your information to or share it with other organisations?**

As a Government Department we do not share data with other organisations unless the law permits us to do so. We do not sell individual information. We will share it only with our authorised Data Processors who must act at all times on our instructions as the Data Controller under the Data Protection Act 1998. Before you submit any information, we will notify you as to why we are asking for specific information and it is completely up to you whether or not you want to provide it.

**Your data is kept under secure conditions**

We take appropriate steps to maintain the security of your data on our website. You should understand that the open nature of the Internet is such that data may flow over networks without security measures and may be accessed and used by people other than those for whom the data is intended. Our intention is that this should not happen and we take measures to ensure that it does not.

**Collection of Information**

We collect personally identifiable information, like names, postal addresses, email addresses, etc., when voluntarily submitted by our visitors. The information you provide is used to fulfill you specific request. The registered members of our website are automatically added to our site announcement mailing list. You as a subscriber of the mailing list have the option to opt out of these mailing list by clicking on the unsubscribe link in any of the newsletter sent to you. The unsubscribe process is automatic and immediate. This site uses a tool which collects your requests for pages and passes elements of them to search engines to assist them in indexing this site. We control the configuration of the tool and are responsible for any information sent to the search engines.

**Cookie/Tracking Technology**

The Site may use cookie and tracking technology depending on the features offered. Cookie and tracking technology are useful for gathering information such as browser type and operating system, tracking the number of visitors to the Site, and understanding how visitors use the Site. Cookies can also help customize the Site for visitors. Personal information cannot be collected via cookies and other tracking technology, however, if you previously provided personally identifiable information, cookies may be tied to such information. Aggregate cookie and tracking information may be shared with third parties.

**Distribution of Information**

We may share information with governmental agencies or other companies assisting us in fraud prevention or investigation. We may do so when: (1) permitted or required by law; or, (2) trying to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud or unauthorized transactions; or, (3) investigating fraud which has already taken place. The information is not provided to these companies for marketing purposes. Other than this, we have our own network of websites and portals. From time to time, we may send you the relevant information from these websites or portals also. 

**Commitment to Data Security  **

Your personally identifiable information is kept secure. Only authorized employees, agents and contractors (who have agreed to keep information secure and confidential) have access to this information. All emails and newsletters from this site allow you to opt out of further mailings, as already mentioned above. 

**Ad Serving**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies.
